You smoke, Teach?
Five days ago, a battle broke out in the Modello
between a number of Lylat and Galgad spies.
Our people were able to find the Lylat spies' corpses,
but we don't have any details on the
Galgad team's specifics or whereabouts.
They've evaded our efforts to find them.
So wait, the place where Thea and the others are
is a total powder keg right now?!
It is.
I shouldn't have been so careless.
Under rare circumstances,
cornered spies will turn to desperate acts of violence.
All we can do is pray that the others
don't get dragged into the situation.
Modello Entertainment District -
Four Days Before the Others Began Their Search
MISSION: Forgetter II
Who are you?
I'm this girl's mother.
Matilda Barbet...
So, you're a technician for Mirakoff Heavy Industries,
a machining company from the Lylat Kingdom.
I've heard of them.
When their machines break down,
they send techs out from Lylat to repair them.
That's right.
I'm here to service the hotel's fountain.
So, what's this about you being Annette's mom?
Four years ago, we were visiting the Republic
when we ended up in a train crash.
They took me to the hospital…
but I had no idea she actually survived.
So wait, who are you?
What do you mean?
I don't get it, yo.
Annette, go play with Erna.
Now that, I get!
C'mon, Erna, let's go have a squirt gun fight!
I don't want to.
Someone, save me.
Long story short,
she's lost all her memories of
everything but the past four years.
She got taken in by the state,
given the name Annette,
and left in the care of a seminary boarding school.
We're her friends,
and we're all out on holiday together.
I'm sorry to have to tell you,
but Annette doesn't remember anything about you.
It can't be…
I'm afraid that we can't just nod along
and hand her over to you.
Not to be rude, but there's no hard proof
that you're actually her mother,
and we would have to consult with the school
before we did anything anyways.
So, you're telling me that
my daughter's lost her memories
and has been living a completely different life
here in the Republic?
No, I should be thanking God for the fact
that she's alive and that I got to see her again.
I'm just glad she seems happy.
Has Annette always been such a wild child?
Oh, yes.
She would always sneak on to my job sites
and fiddle with the machines.
I never taught her how,
but she soaked up information like a sponge.
Ah, that makes sense.
So, that's where she got her engineering skills.
We should leave.
The pool's closing soon.
Please…
I know it's selfish of me to ask,
but would you let me have dinner with her tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
Reading romance novels, are we?
It's intellectual curiosity, that's all.
Also, put on some clothes
before you come out on the balcony.
It's fine. It's not like there's anyone around to see.
I'm literally right here.
I could bare it all, if you'd like.
I hate you so much.
I'm planning on letting Matilda and Annette
see each other tomorrow.
Any objections?
Why bother?
They're just going to get split up again.
What good will letting them get attached do?
She was so empty.
That's how it felt when I looked into Annette's heart.
She had no reason for wanting to be a spy
and no reason to want to stay on Lamplight.
I don't see how my teammates'
personal lives are my problem.
The team needs her.
Even I have to admit she's talented.
It's a perfect replica.
She made this for me
after taking a single glance at my purse.
It looks the exact same as the off-the-shelf model,
but if you give it a light flick…
it tosses out these bouncy balls.
They're made of metal coated in rubber,
so they can be used as throwing weapons.
Now, I can carry three of them around with me
hidden in a unassuming purse.
That Annette…
Her ability to memorize things is incredible.
Pretty ironic, an amnesiac having a great memory.
Look, I'm not expecting you to help.
All I ask is that you watch quietly from the side.
You want me to sit back and do nothing, huh?
If that makes you feel like a hypocrite,
then try this on for size.
If Annette finds a strong reason
for wanting to be a spy,
that could have huge benefits for Lamplight.
Fine, knock yourself out.
But I have two conditions.
Go on.
I'm coming to the dinner tomorrow.
I need to make sure you don't get any funny ideas
about handing Annette over to her.
That's fine by me.
What's your other condition?
You need to stay with those two
and make sure they don't embarrass me.
I'm a mature adult lady,
so I want a dress that's cool and elegant, yo!
Shut up!
I don’t give a rat's ass what you want!
The jam went flying all over my dress!
Don't you move one more inch!
This should be interesting.
One of them has amnesia, sure,
but they're still related.
I'm looking forward to seeing how
she gets through to Annette.
Me too.
I just hope they're able to get
on the same wavelength.
So…
Annette? Is that what your name is now?
Yep.
Have you been staying healthy?
You haven't been getting hurt or sick, have you?
I'm aces, yo.
Oh, that's so good to hear.
I was worried sick about you all last night.
Oh hey, samesies.
You were concerned about me?
I was worried about my health too, yo.
It's kind of scary how out of sync they are.
This just feels cruel.
You really think she's going to want
Annette back after that?
You're right.
Once the dessert comes, we should...
Erna?
I smell misfortune coming.
We're surrounded.
Pretend you're getting up to go to the bathroom.
We're going to slip out the back.
May I ask what's going on?
Keep your voice down and follow me.
Careful there.
Are you all right, ma'am?
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I think I had a bit too much to drink.
Here, I'll walk you back to your table.
That's really not necessary.
Let me stay like this for a second, and I'll be fine.
There are three shady-looking men.
They noticed you're not coming back,
and they're on the move.
That wasn't on purpose!
Oh, dear.
Are you all right?
Sorry about that.
I'm going to take her to the little girls' room.
Do you know who they are?
No one respectable, that's for sure.
You need to hurry, or they'll catch you.
You say that, but there's nothing around here
but sea and mountains.
Can you get rid of them?
I could, but I'd rather not fire my gun
this close to the restaurant.
Just run along the side of the cliff.
Follow the sound of the bell.
The what?
Just do it.
This way.
O-okay.
There! She ran that way!
Don't let her get away!
She's got a friend with her!
Snag 'em both!
I sent an assassin on ahead.
One who breaks all the rules and
can bury her foes without a single weapon,
or letting them sense a whiff of hostility.
How unlucky…
I'm code name Fool,
and it's time to kill with everything.
Are you being hunted?
That's not...
Unless you tell me what's going on,
I can't let you see Annette anymore.
They're debt collectors.
Do elaborate.
It all started two days ago.
I was taking a breather in the park
after finishing up a job,
but when I set down my toolbox,
someone came and stole it.
I looked everywhere I could,
but they'd already sold it to a pawnshop.
That's when I panicked.
I put up my passport as collateral to borrow money
so I could gamble enough to buy it back, but I lost big.
Of course you did.
Just forget the dumb toolbox and go home without it.
But there are really important things in there.
Some mom she is.
She can't hold a decent conversation
with her own daughter,
and on top of that, she's loaded with debt.
I say we dump her off at the embassy
and be done with it!
Come on, keep your voice down.
It isn't Matilda's fault she got robbed.
Uh-huh.
This girl is an angel.
Say what now?
There I was, in the depths of despair,
and she came to me.
She looked just a glittering angel.
I thought my daughter was dead,
but now, we've been reunited.
What would you call that, if not a miracle?!
All I want is to live together with my daughter again.
Please, let me have that second chance!
See, now she's just talking nonsense.
I've seen it, yo.
Annette?
The toolbox was cobalt blue,
like the color of the sky.
Someone used to carry it around so proudly.
Are your memories coming back?!
But back then, it was so large, and so heavy,
and so hard, and so close…
Nope, I can't remember a thing!
Matilda...
Would you mind if I went
and got that toolbox back for you?
MISSION: Forgetter II
What? Did you come to stop me?
There's no need to help her out like this.
Is the reward really worth all this risk?
I told you already.
I want to fill up Annette's empty heart.
And what if doing that makes her
stop wanting to be a spy?
Then Annette can go back to being a normal girl.
Monika?
There are too many soldiers around.
It's been bothering me all day.
They've been prowling the city since this afternoon.
Don't you think that's weird?
What are you getting at?
Something messy is going down
right here in this city.
You still sure you want to do this?
Oh, yes.
You really are an idiot.
And after that hit you took this afternoon, too.
If you'd taken the radio, given the orders yourself,
and left Matilda to me,
that all would have gone a whole lot smoother.
I was the one who put us in that situation.
I couldn't let someone else shoulder all the danger,
and the same is true here.
Like I said, you're an idiot.
And when you get hurt, it makes me
look like I'm not doing my job.
So, I'll lend you a hand.
You really-
Come on, take a hint.
I've got my ego to uphold,
and when my teammates get injured,
it reflects badly on me.
If you're not willing to stand down,
then what choice do I have?
Just this once, I'll play along with
your goody-two-shoes nonsense.
I'm here to help.
Me too, yo!
All right, let's do this!
With the four of us together, there's nothing we can't-
Please, you can skip the big speech.
We're gonna cooperate our way,
and we're gonna do it with the pride of knowing
that we were the chosen ones.
This is the one.
A regular old toolbox would never
sell at a price that high.
Excuse me, I have something I'd like to sell.
Would you mind?
Let's see it.
It's this toolbox.
Would you buy it from me?
No way!
This toolbox is the exact same
as the one over in the display case there.
Would you be willing to give me
seventy percent of the sale price?
I memorized everything about it, yo.
Gimme an hour, and I'll have it finished.
Thanks for waiting!
H-how can it be the exact same?
Can you help us out?
It was really precious to her father.
Be that as it may, my hands are tied.
Please, sir, we really need the money.
What do you say?
This is the hotel we're staying at.
Don't hesitate to give me a call
if you change your mind.
What a shame.
Yeah.
Go on ahead back to the hotel.
I'll be there as soon as I'm done with my shopping.
You got it.
This is Dreamspeaker.
Stage one is complete.
I saw right through that shopkeeper's desires.
He's a money-grubber, just like we suspected.
Copy that.
This is Fool.
Stage two is complete.
The toolbox got stolen, just like we planned.
That means the pawnshop and the thieves
are definitely in cahoots.
Still, that was fast.
It disappeared while I was distracted
by a fountain show.
You're like a pickpocket's wet dream.
Now that you mention it,
I think my purse is missing, too.
Annette, how's that transmitter looking?
It's working like a charm!
And it's pretty close, too.
Got it.
Can you give me the coordinates?
Looks like a couple of lowlifes who
couldn't hack it as a real gang.
Well, that's fine by me.
Time to finish this.
So, you steal valuables from tourists,
sell them to that pawnshop,
put them up for outrageous prices,
lend money to your desperate marks,
and direct them to your casinos?
This is one messed-up operation you're running.
Who the hell are you?
Just a girl on vacation.
That's a whole lot of passports
you've snatched up as collateral.
Yep, figures.
Hands off the merch!
Wow, rude.
I'd be happy to take you all out myself,
but this time, I'm handing off the honors.
Yo, is it my time to shine?
I'm code name Forgetter,
and it's time to put it all together, yo!
How were you able to get it back?
Who exactly are you all?
I have a relative on the force.
All I did was ask them to do me a little favor.
Actually, we used that secret ledger we stole
to blackmail the shop owner.
I am sorry, though.
We weren't able to find your passport.
That's a shame…
Forget that stuff!
Show me what's inside, yo!
Sure, I would be happy to.
I've been looking forward to this so much,
I couldn't sleep last night!
I want to make sure that only the right people
get caught in my traps.
How can I do that?
You mean, when you're pulling pranks?
Well, you could try using this paint.
Ooh, how does it work?
It's a new kind of paint we just developed.
It dissolves when it gets wet.
Maybe you could try only telling your friends
how to tell it apart from other paint.
Ooh!
This, I can get behind!
That's probably how they used to communicate,
back before.
There's something I should say, for the record.
I hate Annette's guts.
Why?
Isn't it obvious?!
She always bullies me!
Oh, right.
But…
it would still make me sad if she left.
Please, don't get the wrong idea.
I don't think that woman would
make a very good mother.
If Annette wants to go live with Matilda,
I'll do everything I can to talk her out of it.
Yeep?
But if she truly makes up her mind to go,
then that's her choice.
I think that's a very noble way
to approach things, Big Sis Thea.
I appreciate it.
And can you tell what this part is?
Ooh, I wonder?
So, this is what having a mom is like.
I'm gonna try this out on Erna first, yo!
I changed my mind.
Please leave now.
Good work, everyone.
You too, Monika.
Matilda was over the moon,
and it's all thanks to you.
We should probably go ahead
and tell Klaus about her.
I wonder how Teach will react?
I'm a little scared.
Nah, I'd say those specific fears are misguided.
What do you mean?
It smelled fishy.
The army was descending on the city,
and that woman refused to go to the cops
after she got her stuff stolen.
I checked out my hunch,
and sure enough, it was right.
I found Matilda's passport.
The thing is, it had a different name on it.
You liar, you told us you never found it at all!
I've been spending the past day investigating
to make absolutely sure.
So, thanks.
I wouldn't have gotten to the
bottom of this if not for you all.
The fact is, Matilda's an Imperial spy.
I'll go ahead and report in to Klaus.
After all, we've got a responsibility to
hand Matilda over to the military.